<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on </title>
    <link>https://pawelropa.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on </description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 14:01:02 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://pawelropa.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>superhuman by habit</title>
      <link>https://pawelropa.github.io/post/superhuman-by-habit/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 14 Oct 2014 14:01:02 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelropa.github.io/post/superhuman-by-habit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Good habits are essential to every productive person, I have been working on them very hard for over a year now. During this time I have read a few books on this topic, recently &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Willpower-Instinct-Self-Control-Works-Matters/dp/1583335080&#34;&gt;The Willpower Instinct by Kelly McGonigal Ph.D&lt;/a&gt;. Today I would like to talk about &lt;a href=&#34;tynan.com&#34;&gt;Tynan&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; new book namely &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Superhuman-Habit-Becoming-Possible-Yourself-ebook/dp/B00NGC8I9E&#34;&gt;Superhuman by Habit&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book is segmented into two main parts - building habits and choosing them. It&amp;rsquo;s quite condensed, a good reader could finish entire book in one go, which I really like and it does not contain all the unnecessary fillers which are pretty common in other publications. Let&amp;rsquo;s face it an average person does not need to know which enzyme is important for building habits or a ton of research which a claim is backed by. I mean, it is good to know this but it is not essential. In my opinion it is used to establish credibility, Tynan does not need that, I mean look at the number of blog posts he has written over the years, not to mention a few books, his projects like &lt;a href=&#34;sett.com&#34;&gt;Sett&lt;/a&gt; and others, clearly he has some good habits which make him quite productive person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the chapters which I specially liked, talked about humans and how we are a creatures of habits. Every single person is driven by good and bad ones.
It might be silly but previously I did&amp;rsquo;t look at it that way. Habits were only good, if I did&amp;rsquo;t exercise on the morning but just drink coffee and browsed the web, this wasn&amp;rsquo;t considered by me as a bed habit.
I kind of subconsciously always thought about them in a positive light and ignored bad ones. This was a mistake. One should acknowledge all ones habits, bad and good ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly it is as easy to execute good as well as bad ones, the difference is, as Tynan points out, in effort to develop them. It is very easy to not exercise or start your day properly, but once you have those habits in place it is automatic, you don&amp;rsquo;t even think about it, you just do it.
If you are serious about developing habits I would recommend &lt;a href=&#34;http://tinyhabits.com&#34;&gt;tinyhabbits&lt;/a&gt;. BJ Fogg has a week long FREE course which might help you. Basic premise is when you starting developing them start small, very small even and chain them to action which you already repeat daily.
Specifically you would like to develop exercise habit, put your workout cloths very close to your bed, when you get up the first thing you do is to get dressed and walk outside your house. Once you there you start small, let&amp;rsquo;s say run for a one minute or so, the point is to establish consistency first than increase the volume of exercise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going back to the book, Tynan makes a very good point you don&amp;rsquo;t have to perform extraordinary at first. The crucial thing is to actually execute, if you don&amp;rsquo;t like running just walk for five minutes, if you don&amp;rsquo;t like writing just write a specific number of words without style or anything but write it! Skipping one day is acceptable, but force yourself to do your repeated action of choice. Don&amp;rsquo;t ever skip two days. It is basically a kill switch to your habit.
&amp;gt; Remember that the power of habit isn&amp;rsquo;t actually in the individual execution, but in the consistency. It is far worse to skip doing something than to just do a terrible job of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall I have really enjoyed the book, it is full of small tips which will help you develop good habits faster, you will not stumble on trying to find out what works and what not. If you are really into personal development as I am then this book is a must for you, and I really recommend it. You can order it from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/Superhuman-Habit-Becoming-Possible-Yourself-ebook/dp/B00NGC8I9E&#34;&gt;amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>reasons why you should switch to dvorak</title>
      <link>https://pawelropa.github.io/post/reasons-why-you-should-switch-to-dvorak/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Sep 2014 14:00:29 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelropa.github.io/post/reasons-why-you-should-switch-to-dvorak/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Laptop is the most important device for many people around the world. Every software developer, like me, spends countless hours typing, thus one may argue keyboard is one of essential interfaces through which we interact with computer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being fanatic of productivity makes me think very often about optimisations which can be applied to my live, productivity hacks but also about my health. Being healthy, staying in good shape makes me feel fantastic and thus happy, which is of crucial importance to producing great work. Ok, but how it is related to DVORAK?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most popular keyboard layout used throughout the world is QWERTY. How is that it gained such popularity? Reason is simple - legacy. Now some of software engineers are probably starting to think it means trouble, and they are right.
Let us start with a little bit of history. Typing machines are mechanical devices, that were common in nineteenth and twentieth century, well &lt;a href=&#34;http://time.com/2986091/germany-may-counter-u-s-spying-with-typewriters/&#34;&gt;they might shine again it seems&amp;hellip;&lt;/a&gt; The first models had major flow in their design, which caused the devices to &lt;strong&gt;jam a lot&lt;/strong&gt;. To &lt;strong&gt;prevent this&lt;/strong&gt; from happening &lt;strong&gt;QWERTY layout was developed&lt;/strong&gt;.
When computer keyboards were invented, it was decided to use a layout which people already knew. Today we have keyboard layout which is used throughout the world which wasn&amp;rsquo;t designed for speed and efficiency. If you look at it on the world scale this is a big wast of time, but I can live with that, most humans are wasting a lot of time anyway.
Looking from a software development perspective, producing quality code, designing good architecture of a product, knowledge of algorithms, ability to work in a team and so on, are more important qualities of a software engineer than his typing speed.
It was a long digression, but we needed a little bit of history, and knowledge why things are the way they are. More important, I needed to point out that typing speed, is not crucial argument for switching to different keyboard layout, but it is repeated on the internet as the most valid one, and in my opinion it&amp;rsquo;s a folly.
&lt;strong&gt;The reason for switching to different keyboard layout is health related.&lt;/strong&gt; When you use QWERTY, most important keys (based on the frequency of use) are not right under your fingers. You have to make additional movement every single time when typing &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Letter_frequency&#34;&gt;most frequent letters&lt;/a&gt;. Typing eight hours a day, five days a week, each month, each year is very tiresome for your hands. If the layout is not natural and designed for less movement it makes this burden even bigger. Eventually it might lead to Repetitive Strain Injury (RSI), as it was in my case. I forced it a little bit working over 12 hours a day for months on end, but hey those personal projects of mine, will not write themselves right?
Eventually the pain escalated and typing even six hours a day made my hands hurt, preventing me from enjoying my work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have read about DVORAK before, but decided switching wasn&amp;rsquo;t worth it based on following reasons:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;my typing speed will be down dramatically,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;searching for letters will prevent me from getting into the zone,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;other people usually use QWERTY, I will not be able to use their computers right from the get go,&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;VIM is not designed for DVORAK.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My opinion did not changed, if your only reason for switch is you want to type faster, it is not worth it. You can easily type 100 wpm on QWERTY, start using metronome and you will get there. Those arguments against switching were invalidated by pain in my wrists, and supposedly typing on DVORAK layout &lt;a href=&#34;http://matt.might.net/articles/preventing-and-managing-rsi/&#34;&gt;should eliminate RSI&lt;/a&gt;, so I made a conscious decision to change layout and since I were  switching, I might as well shoot two birds at one time so I have chosen &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.kaufmann.no/roland/dvorak/&#34;&gt;programmers edition&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not wanting to hinder my work more, I took a weekend when I didn&amp;rsquo;t do any contract work, memorised the keyboard layout and started to type. It turned out one weekend wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough. What I have started to notice, after a week or so my wrists didn&amp;rsquo;t hurt anymore which was refreshing, and at that point I knew I will not be going back. In the end it took more than a month but I regained my typing speed, now I type faster than before and with less effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;del&gt;DVORAK FOREVER!!!&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunatelly after playing with DVORAK for a while I must say, the switch is not worth it. There are multiple reasons, the biggest one is - all word is running on QWERTY. What this means, almost all apps, all computers are configured with this layout in mind, after a while it becomes tiresome - remapping shortcuts, configuring each application, each computer. Thus personally I would strongly advice against the switch, in fact after this long jurney I am back to QUERTY.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evolution of iOS</title>
      <link>https://pawelropa.github.io/post/evolution-of-ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Jul 2014 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelropa.github.io/post/evolution-of-ios/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s important to know when a specific feature was introduced in which iOS, especially when there are some backwards compatibility issues, that&amp;rsquo;s the reason behind this article. I tried to make the descriptions of new features as short as possible, to give only a general idea.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ios-4-0&#34;&gt;iOS 4.0&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;multitasking&#34;&gt;Multitasking&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apps go into background mode when user presses home button. Previous versions of iOS terminated the app. Most of the apps after going to background mode are being suspended but there are some exceptions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An application can request a finite amount of time to complete some important task.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An application can declare itself as supporting specific services that require regular background execution time.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;An application can use local notifications to generate user alerts at designated times, whether or not the application is running.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app which is in background mode can still be terminated due to some conditions for example low memory, therefore the applications must be ready to exit at any time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;blocks&#34;&gt;Blocks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really great feature making source code cleaner and developer&amp;rsquo;s live a lot easier. Block are segments of code that can be passed to methods and functions, get invoked, assigned to properties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;gcd&#34;&gt;GCD&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thread programming is hard, no question about it, how about making a simpler alternative which is really easy to use? That&amp;rsquo;s where GCD (Grand Central Dispatch) comes in. No more blocking of main thread, apps are now more responsive (if written right)!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;local-notifications&#34;&gt;Local Notifications&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app can issue a local notification, which will inform a user about an important event. Mostly used when the app is in the background mode.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;event-kit&#34;&gt;Event Kit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Provides an interface for accessing calendar events on a user’s device. You can use this framework to get existing events and add new events to the user’s calendar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;core-motion&#34;&gt;Core Motion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How about getting info about iPhone state form motion-based sensors, and using it to build a game where you can manipulate a ball through rotating the device? Sounds great? You can do it with the use of Core Motion framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-protection&#34;&gt;Data Protection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Build in encryption can now be used when working with sensitive user data.
&amp;gt;When your application designates a particular file as protected, the system stores that file on-disk in an encrypted format. While the device is locked, the contents of the file are inaccessible to both your application and to any potential intruders. However, when the device is unlocked by the user, a decryption key is created to allow your application to access the file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Implementing data protection requires you to be considerate in how you create and manage the data you want to protect. Applications must themselves be designed to secure the data at creation time and to be prepared for changes in access to that data when the user locks and unlocks the device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;core-telephony&#34;&gt;Core Telephony&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This framework provides interfaces for interacting with phone-based information on devices that have a cellular radio. Apps can get information about a user’s cellular service provider and be notified when call events occur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;iad&#34;&gt;iAd&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Advertisements framework allows a developer to monetize an app in different way.
Why would anyone spoil the app with ads?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;quicklook-framework&#34;&gt;QuickLook Framework&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Quick Look framework for iOS, allows to preview the contents of files an app does not support directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;av-foundation&#34;&gt;AV Foundation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;rsquo;s the bomb! Very powerful framework which allows developers to do a ton of crazy stuff. Playing audio, video, recording and so on. You should definitely check it out!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;asset-library&#34;&gt;Asset Library&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A framework which provide interface for retrieving a user’s photos and videos. Using this framework, you can access the same assets that are managed by the Photos application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;image-i-o&#34;&gt;Image I/O&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Importing and exporting image data and image metadata.
&amp;gt;This framework is built on top of the Core Graphics data types and functions and supports all of the standard image types available in iOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;core-media&#34;&gt;Core Media&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even more powerful than AV Foundation which is build on top of it. Check it out if you are interested in more low-level stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;cored-video&#34;&gt;Cored Video&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funny apple description, they make it sound as some scary black magic is going on inside this framework. More reasons to check it out!
&amp;gt;The Core Video framework (CoreVideo.framework) provides buffer and buffer pool support for Core Media. Most applications should never need to use this framework directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ios-4-1&#34;&gt;iOS 4.1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;game-center&#34;&gt;Game Center&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Games becoming more social with use of this framework. User can create it&amp;rsquo;s own profile which will be universal. Leaderboards, matchmaking and achievements mean users will gets more fun interacting with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ios-4-2&#34;&gt;iOS 4.2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;printing&#34;&gt;Printing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iOS now incorporates support for wireless printing from iPhone and iPad applications.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;air-play&#34;&gt;Air Play&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Audio streaming to Apple TV and to third-party AirPlay speakers and receivers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;core-midi&#34;&gt;Core MIDI&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Provides a standard way to communicate with MIDI devices, including hardware keyboards and synthesisers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;weak-linking-support&#34;&gt;Weak Linking Support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;System frameworks now tag their classes with availability information that the compiler can use to link weakly to those classes as needed. It is easer to check if the class is available at the runtime. Previously, you needed to use the NSClassFromString function to determine whether a class was present, now you can simply check for the existence the class directly with the use of &lt;em&gt;class&lt;/em&gt; method. Generally speaking these feature makes life easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ios-4-3&#34;&gt;iOS 4.3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;air-play-video-support&#34;&gt;Air Play Video Support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previous version added support for audio streaming, this allows streaming of video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ios-5-0&#34;&gt;iOS 5.0&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;icloud-storage&#34;&gt;iCloud Storage&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really great feature build for easy access of your data by the NSA in mind. You will have an option to store all your data in a central location, where Apple will keep it &amp;lsquo;secure&amp;rsquo;. Complete erosion of privacy&amp;hellip; nah just kidding (or am I?).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;icloud-backup&#34;&gt;iCloud Backup&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Easier restoration of apps through cloud backup, space is limited so send &lt;strong&gt;only&lt;/strong&gt; the most important ones&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;automatic-reference-counting&#34;&gt;Automatic Reference Counting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Memory management in Objective-C is based on retain count of objects, if retain count is greater than zero object resides in memory, when it gets down to zero the object gets dealloceted. It was developer responsibility to manage the retain count, with the introduction of ARC it is compiler responsibility.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;storyboard&#34;&gt;Storyboard&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Previously if you didn&amp;rsquo;t wanted create the controllers views programatically you could do it using nib files. Each controller had its own nib, storyboard captures your entire user interface in one place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;newsstand-support&#34;&gt;Newsstand Support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Newsstand provides a central place for users to read magazines and newspapers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-frameworks&#34;&gt;New Frameworks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;glkit-framework&#34;&gt;GLKit Framework&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Utility classes that simplify the effort required to create an OpenGL ES 2.0 app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;core-image-framework&#34;&gt;Core Image Framework&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really fast way to apply filters to images and video, uses CPU and GPU processing power. Really powerful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;twitter-framework&#34;&gt;Twitter Framework&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Provides support for sending Twitter requests on behalf of the user and for composing and sending tweets. For requests, the framework handles the user authentication part of the request for you and provides a template for creating the HTTP portion of the request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;accounts-framework&#34;&gt;Accounts Framework&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Provides system wide sign-on model for certain user accounts. Single sign-on improves the user experience, because apps no longer need to prompt a user separately for login information related to an account.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;generic-security-services-framework&#34;&gt;Generic Security Services Framework&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Security related services to iOS apps. Very little info about this one in Apple&amp;rsquo;s developer library, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ietf.org/rfc/rfc2743.txt&#34;&gt;rfc-2743&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://tools.ietf.org/html/rfc4401&#34;&gt;rfc-4401&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;core-bluetooth&#34;&gt;Core Bluetooth&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Framework allows developers to interact specifically with Bluetooth accessories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ios-5-1&#34;&gt;iOS 5.1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;dictation-support&#34;&gt;Dictation support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On supported devices, iOS automatically inserts recognised phrases into the current text view when the user has chosen dictation input. The new UIDictationPhrase class (declared in UITextInput.h) provides you with a string representing a phrase that a user has dictated. In the case of ambiguous dictation results, the new class provides an array containing alternative strings. New methods in the UITextInput protocol allow your app to respond to the completion of dictation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ios-6-0&#34;&gt;iOS 6.0&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;maps&#34;&gt;Maps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apple introduces it&amp;rsquo;s own Map framework to challenge Google.Apps that do not incorporate their own map support now have an easier way to launch the Maps app and display points of interest or directions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;social-frameworks&#34;&gt;Social Frameworks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ever tired of having separate frameworks for Twitter, Facebook or Sina&amp;rsquo;s Weibo?  Managing their versions and keeping everything up to date? Apple response is a framework which unifies all those services.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;pass-kit&#34;&gt;Pass Kit&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pass Kit is a new technology that uses web services, a new file format, and an Objective-C framework (PassKit.framework) to implement support for downloadable passes. Companies can create passes to represent items such as coupons, boarding passes, event tickets, and discount cards for businesses. Instead of carrying a physical representation of these items, users can now store them on their iOS device and use them the same way as before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;reminders&#34;&gt;Reminders&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In previous version Event Kit allowed creation, deletion - general management of calendar events. Since iOS6 it will allow to use reminders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-app-purchases&#34;&gt;In-App Purchases&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Introduction of freemium model and slow death of paid apps. User can now purchase additional content inside the app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;collection-views&#34;&gt;Collection Views&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Really great addition, it&amp;rsquo;s worth to set deployment target to iOS6 (not iOS5) solely for this collection views. Easy way to create more robust user interface.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ui-state-preservation&#34;&gt;UI State Preservation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even when an app gets terminated by the operating system, its now possible to restore user interface to the state when it was last used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;auto-layout&#34;&gt;Auto Layout&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More robust system than previously used &amp;ldquo;springs and struts&amp;rdquo; for laying out user interface elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;data-privacy&#34;&gt;Data Privacy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to location data, the system now asks the user’s permission before allowing third-party apps to access certain user data, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contacts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calendars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reminders&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Photo Library&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ios-6-1&#34;&gt;iOS 6.1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;map-kit-searches&#34;&gt;Map Kit Searches&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Developer is able to programmatically search for map-based addresses and points of interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ios-7-0&#34;&gt;iOS 7.0&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;user-interface-changes&#34;&gt;User Interface Changes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;ui-redesign&#34;&gt;UI Redesign&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The iOS 7 user interface has been completely redesigned.Newly introduced flat design focuses on functionality and on the user’s content informs every aspect of design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;dynamic-behaviours-for-views&#34;&gt;Dynamic Behaviours for Views&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Introduction of physics based animation engine into iOS, more possibilities for creating crazy looking animations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;text-kit&#34;&gt;Text Kit&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New version of iOS focuses more on content, Text Kit framework allows better management of text and typography.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;64-bit-support&#34;&gt;64-Bit Support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When compiled for the 64-bit runtime, apps may run faster because of the availability of extra processor resources in 64-bit mode, they will also use more memory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;multitasking-enhancements&#34;&gt;Multitasking Enhancements&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Apps can now fetch new content, after receiving silent push notification from a server. When fetching is complete, it can inform user about new podcast, tv show, podcast - all process done without user interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;games&#34;&gt;Games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;sprite-kit-framework&#34;&gt;Sprite Kit Framework&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Games are big on App Store, till now there has been no Apple frameworks for creating them, only open source like &lt;a href=&#34;http://cocos2d.org&#34;&gt;cocos2d&lt;/a&gt;.
In fact if you know cocos2d you will adapt the Sprite Kit very quickly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;game-controller-framework&#34;&gt;Game Controller Framework&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This framework standardises the use of third party game controller hardware.
&amp;gt;Game controllers can be devices connected physically to an iOS device or connected wirelessly over Bluetooth. The Game Controller framework notifies your app when controllers become available and lets you specify which controller inputs are relevant to your app.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;game-center-improvements&#34;&gt;Game Center Improvements&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Exchanges which lets you create simultaneous turns, player chats, increased size of leaderboards or conditions in challenges.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;airdrop&#34;&gt;AirDrop&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sharing photos, document, URLs and other kinds of data with nearby iPhones, iPads or Macs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;inter-app-audio&#34;&gt;Inter-App Audio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Audio Unit framework (AudioUnit.framework) adds support for Inter-App Audio, which enables the ability to send MIDI commands and stream audio between apps on the same device. For example, you might use this feature to record music from an app acting as an instrument or use it to send audio to another app for processing. To vend your app’s audio data, publish a I/O audio unit (AURemoteIO) that is visible to other processes. To use audio features from another app, use the audio component discovery interfaces in iOS 7.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;peer-to-peer-connectivity&#34;&gt;Peer-to-Peer Connectivity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Framework for network peer-to-peer interaction between devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ios-7-1&#34;&gt;iOS 7.1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;support-for-external-media-players&#34;&gt;Support for External Media Players&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apps can now receive and respond to events sent by an external media player. This process lets users interact solely with the external media player, removing the need to interact directly with an iOS device.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;opengl-es&#34;&gt;OpenGL ES&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Multithreading support added to OpenGL ES.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;ios-8-0&#34;&gt;iOS 8.0&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;swift&#34;&gt;Swift&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Introduction of new language called Swift, which is designed to be as productive as Ruby and as fast as Ansi C, Objective-C and C++. There are many features which will make this language great&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clean syntax&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No headers and semicolons&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiple return values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generics&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Closures and much much more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;app-extensions&#34;&gt;App Extensions&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Extensions allows custom functionality within a context of a user task. For example if user plays with Apple&amp;rsquo;s photos app and want to share cool picture by your social app called Momo he simply can do it by an extension which you provided from photos app. No need to go to Momo specifically import image and than share it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;touch-id-authentication&#34;&gt;Touch ID Authentication&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More secure access to content inside an app, you can require a user to authenticated before proceeding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;photos&#34;&gt;Photos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;photos-framework&#34;&gt;Photos Framework&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Provides new APIs for working with photo and video assets, including iCloud Photos assets, that are managed by the Photos app. This framework is a more capable alternative to the Assets Library framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;manual-camera-controls&#34;&gt;Manual Camera Controls&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Long awaited feature, AV Foundation now allows for direct control of the camera focus, white balance and exposure settings!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;games-1&#34;&gt;Games&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Technology improvements in iOS 8 make it easier than ever to implement your game’s graphics and audio features. Some of the new additions are Metal (access to high performance A7 GPU), improvements in Scene Kit and Sprite Kit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;health-kit-framework&#34;&gt;Health Kit Framework&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Health Kit makes it easy for apps to share health-related information, whether that information comes from devices connected to an iOS device or is entered manually by the user. The user’s health information is stored in a centralised and secure location. The user can then see all of that data displayed in the Health app.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;home-kit-framework&#34;&gt;Home Kit Framework&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Framework for communicating with devices in a user&amp;rsquo;s home. Easy way to discover devices and configure them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;icloud&#34;&gt;iCloud&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;document-related-data-migration&#34;&gt;Document-Related Data Migration&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When users logs in to iCloud through device running iOS8 all the documents get migrated to a new version of the app&amp;rsquo;s container directory. Devices running older operating systems will continue to have access to the original container, but changes made in that container will not appear in the new container and vice versa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;cloud-kit&#34;&gt;Cloud Kit&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;New great way to store users data without the need to setting up your own server, you have access to 1PB of disc space for free. Cloud Kit gives you control over when transfers occur. You can use Cloud Kit to manage all types of data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;document-picker&#34;&gt;Document Picker&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The document picker view controller grants users access to files outside your application’s sandbox. It is a simple mechanism for sharing documents between apps. It also enables more complex workflows, because users can edit a single document with multiple apps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;handoff&#34;&gt;Handoff&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Handoff enables users to begin an activity on one device, then switch to another device and resume the same activity on the other device. For example, a user who is writing a document moves to an iOS device that&amp;rsquo;s signed into the same Apple ID, and the same document automatically opens on iOS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;unified-storyboards-for-universal-apps&#34;&gt;Unified Storyboards for Universal Apps&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One storyboard to rule them all, you no longer need to use separate storyboards for iPhone and iPad, also with adaptive controllers writing multi device apps will be easier than before.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There you have it, general evolution of iOS since version 4.0 to 8.0. Guys at Apple are working hard and I love how the iOS keeps getting better and better. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to see what the next version will bring!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Morning routine</title>
      <link>https://pawelropa.github.io/post/morning-routine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2014 13:59:31 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelropa.github.io/post/morning-routine/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Getting a proper start on the morning is crucial to achieve high productivity during the rest of a day. It helps you to get into the right mindset.
Rising early is also a common habit among many successful people. Margaret Thatcher was up every day at 5 a.m.; Howard Schultz is an early riser.
When Ted Turner is being asked a question &lt;em&gt;what is the secret to success?&lt;/em&gt; He answers.
&amp;gt; Early to bed, early to rise. Work like hell and advertise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;current-routine&#34;&gt;Current routine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have developed a certain routine that gets me started. The routine is not easy, for it requires me to get up at 5:30 a.m. I am not a morning person, don’t like to oversleep either, but 5:30 much to early for me, therefore I need to force myself (at lest needed to, on the beginning), but it’s worth it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After an early rise I dress up for a workout. It is critically important to have a workout clothes next to an alarm clock (the alarm clock should be a few meters away from your bed). When I don&amp;rsquo;t prepare my clothes earlier, most of the time I simply slip back into bed.
Next I go into a kitchen, where I drink up a glass of water and go out for a morning workout. Usually my workout consists of cycling (1 hour) and pull-ups or running. After this I take a shower, drink water and go meditate for a few minutes just to clear my mind. After a quick meditation I start working.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;benefits&#34;&gt;Benefits&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Being a developer means one spend most of the time in front of a computer. This sedentary lifestyle is really bad for ones health, therefore working out is crucially important.
Whenever I neglect my morning routine for three or four days in a row, I start to feel really bad. My efficiency drops, I start feeling less happy, less energetic. &lt;strong&gt;Bottom line, my morning routine helps me cut through my tasks like a laser.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;changes&#34;&gt;Changes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some changes which I will be making to my morning routine (I love to improve things). I would like to write more blog posts and learn spanish a little bit. Due to high workload I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to make this changes yet, but I will soon. What I would like to avoid is adding to many tasks, I&amp;rsquo;m afraid it would make my mourning routine less enjoyable and more difficult to get into the right mindset.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;create-routine&#34;&gt;Create routine&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like to create your own morning routined I have a few quick tips. Don&amp;rsquo;t try to overload yourself with the tasks. Start small and then go from there. If you want to get up early, go to sleep around 10PM. If you still can’t work at 5, than 6 is also ok.
There is a reason why I do workout first, meditation second and no the other way around; it helps me wake up.
I will repeat myself &lt;em&gt;have everything prepared&lt;/em&gt;, it will really help. Creating morning routine will not be easy, but
&amp;gt;If there is a will, there is a way&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Markdown and Ghost</title>
      <link>https://pawelropa.github.io/post/markdown-and-ghost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2014 13:59:05 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelropa.github.io/post/markdown-and-ghost/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-markdown&#34;&gt;What is markdown&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a plain text formating syntax, which is easy to read, optionally it can be converted to HTML.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-use-it&#34;&gt;Why use it&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because it is really easy, fast and powerfull. Without markdown one can use basically text editor and &lt;strong&gt;mouse&lt;/strong&gt; to format text, the other option is to write text in pure HTML to format it nicely, but it&amp;rsquo;s much harder (nobody really want to type those ugly tags).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;syntax&#34;&gt;Syntax&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;headers&#34;&gt;Headers&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;H1 header
=========
H2 header
---------

or as a alternative
#H1
##H2
###H3
####H4
#####H5
######H6

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;h1-header&#34;&gt;H1 header&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;h2-header&#34;&gt;H2 header&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;h1&#34;&gt;H1&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;h2&#34;&gt;H2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;h3&#34;&gt;H3&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;h4&#34;&gt;H4&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&#34;h5&#34;&gt;H5&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;h6 id=&#34;h6&#34;&gt;H6&lt;/h6&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;emphasis&#34;&gt;Emphasis&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Italics, with *asterisks* or _underscores_.

Bold, with **asterisks** or __underscores__.

Combine bold with italics **asterisks and _underscores_**.

Strikethrough uses two tildes. ~~Scratch this.~~
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Italics, with &lt;em&gt;asterisks&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;underscores&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bold, with &lt;strong&gt;asterisks&lt;/strong&gt; or &lt;strong&gt;underscores&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combine bold with italics &lt;strong&gt;asterisks and &lt;em&gt;underscores&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Strikethrough uses two tildes. &lt;del&gt;Scratch this.&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;unordered-lists&#34;&gt;Unordered lists&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;* Unordered list can use asterisks
- minuses
+ or pluses
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unordered list can use asterisks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;minuses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;or pluses&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Use whichever suits you best, personaly I like to asterisks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;ordered-lists&#34;&gt;Ordered Lists&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;1. First ordered list item
2. Another item
 * Unordered sub-list.
1. Actual numbers don&#39;t matter, just that it&#39;s a number
 1. Ordered sub-list
 4. And another item.
  Paragraphs within list items, just start with the leading space

  To have a line break without a paragraph, you will need to use two trailing spaces.  
  Note that this line is separate, but within the same paragraph.  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;links&#34;&gt;Links&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;[click github](https://www.github.com)
[click github](https://www.github.com &amp;quot;Github&#39;s Homepage Hint&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.github.com&#34;&gt;click github&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.github.com&#34; title=&#34;Github&#39;s Homepage Hint&#34;&gt;click github with hint&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;images&#34;&gt;Images&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Inline-style:
![alt text](https://ghost.org/assets/logos-d976c73a12a1a34a3db6be321db81f71.png &amp;quot;Logo Title Text 1&amp;quot;)

Reference-style:
![alt text][logo]


&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;code-and-syntax-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code and Syntax Highlighting&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code blocks are part of the Markdown spec, but syntax highlighting isn&amp;rsquo;t. To add highlighting into ghost read &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.davebalmer.com/adding-syntax-highlighting-to-ghost/&#34; title=&#34;Add highlighting to Ghost blog&#34;&gt;in this blog post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;tables&#34;&gt;Tables&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the moment Ghost does not support tables. Hopefully it will in the near future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;blockquotes&#34;&gt;Blockquotes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;gt; Blockquotes are very handy in email to emulate reply text.
&amp;gt; This line is part of the same quote.

Quote break.

&amp;gt; This is a very long line that will still be quoted properly when it wraps. Oh boy let&#39;s keep writing to make sure this is long enough to actually wrap for everyone. Oh, you can *put* **Markdown** into a blockquote.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Blockquotes are very handy in email to emulate reply text.
This line is part of the same quote.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Quote break.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is a very long line that will still be quoted properly when it wraps. Oh boy let&amp;rsquo;s keep writing to make sure this is long enough to actually wrap for everyone. Oh, you can &lt;em&gt;put&lt;/em&gt; &lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt; into a blockquote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;horizontal-rule&#34;&gt;Horizontal Rule&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;inline-html&#34;&gt;Inline HTML&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using HTML is very simple in markdown&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;ul&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Item 1&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Item 2&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;
 &amp;lt;/ul&amp;gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Item 1&lt;/li&gt;
 &lt;li&gt;Item 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;line-breaks&#34;&gt;Line Breaks&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To manipulate line breaks use &lt;em&gt;space&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Enter&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet enim. Etiam ullamcorper.

Suspendisse a pellentesque dui, non felis. Maecenas malesuada elit lectus felis, malesuada ultricies.
Curabitur et ligula. Ut molestie a, ultricies porta urna.

Vestibulum commodo volutpat a, convallis ac, laoreet enim. Phasellus fermentum in, dolor. Pellentesque facilisis. Nulla imperdiet sit amet magna. Vestibulum dapibus, mauris nec malesuada fames ac turpis velit, rhoncus eu, luctus et interdum adipiscing wisi. Aliquam erat ac ipsum. Integer aliquam purus. Quisque lorem tortor fringilla sed, vestibulum id, eleifend justo vel bibendum sapien massa ac turpis faucibus orci luctus non, consectetuer lobortis quis, varius in, purus. Integer ultrices posuere cubilia Curae, Nulla ipsum dolor lacus, suscipit adipiscing. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet enim. Etiam ullamcorper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suspendisse a pellentesque dui, non felis. Maecenas malesuada elit lectus felis, malesuada ultricies.
Curabitur et ligula. Ut molestie a, ultricies porta urna.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vestibulum commodo volutpat a, convallis ac, laoreet enim. Phasellus fermentum in, dolor. Pellentesque facilisis. Nulla imperdiet sit amet magna. Vestibulum dapibus, mauris nec malesuada fames ac turpis velit, rhoncus eu, luctus et interdum adipiscing wisi. Aliquam erat ac ipsum. Integer aliquam purus. Quisque lorem tortor fringilla sed, vestibulum id, eleifend justo vel bibendum sapien massa ac turpis faucibus orci luctus non, consectetuer lobortis quis, varius in, purus. Integer ultrices posuere cubilia Curae, Nulla ipsum dolor lacus, suscipit adipiscing. Cum sociis natoque penatibus et&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>code highlighting in ghost</title>
      <link>https://pawelropa.github.io/post/code-highlighting-in-ghost/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2014 13:58:32 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelropa.github.io/post/code-highlighting-in-ghost/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ghost.org/&#34;&gt;Ghost blogging platform&lt;/a&gt; is great. It suits my needs almost perfectly as I don&amp;rsquo;t need a colossal blogging platform with millions of plugins (and security vulnerabilities) like &lt;a href=&#34;https://wordpress.com&#34;&gt;Wordpress&lt;/a&gt;. The posts editor is top notch, really like the preview functionality.
For &lt;a href=&#34;https://ghost.org/&#34;&gt;Ghost&lt;/a&gt; to be perfect I needed to add two main features; comments and code highlighting. This post will be about the latter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are multiple choices for the javascript code which highlights syntax. I looked at &lt;a href=&#34;http://highlightjs.org&#34;&gt;highlightjs&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://prismjs.com&#34;&gt;prism&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://alexgorbatchev.com/SyntaxHighlighter/&#34;&gt;SyntaxHighlighter&lt;/a&gt;. The best for my blog&amp;rsquo;s current theme seemed &lt;a href=&#34;http://prismjs.com&#34;&gt;prism&lt;/a&gt;, which I eventually used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is an example of what ruby code looks like with highlighting done by prism.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hex = [(0..9),(&#39;A&#39;..&#39;F&#39;)]
hex.each { |x| x.each { |y| print y }}    # outputs, 0123456789ABCDEF

# declare an array of arrays
nums = [[0,1], [2,3,4,5,6,7], [8,9], [&#39;A&#39;,&#39;B&#39;,&#39;C&#39;,&#39;D&#39;,&#39;E&#39;,&#39;F&#39;]]
binary = nums[0]                         # =&amp;gt; [0, 1]

a = [0, 1, 2, 3, 4, 5]    # array of 6 elements
b = a.map { |x| 2**x }    # =&amp;gt; [1, 2, 4, 8, 16, 32]
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;installing-prism&#34;&gt;Installing Prism&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go to &lt;a href=&#34;http://prismjs.com/download.html&#34;&gt;prism download site&lt;/a&gt;, choose one of many themes (I personally use &lt;em&gt;Default&lt;/em&gt; theme, it looks nicely with my greyish, modified version of Casper theme), select languages for which you want to add syntax highlighting (you can also add plugins i.e. line numbers).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Download your custom made &lt;strong&gt;prism.js&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;prism.css&lt;/strong&gt; files.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Now you need to upload those files onto the server which hosts your blog. Great hosting site which I use and highly recommend is &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitalocean.com/?refcode=398e0cb398b4&#34;&gt;DigitalOcean&lt;/a&gt;. For upload I like to use &lt;code&gt;scp&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cd /directory/where/your/prisms/files/are
$ scp prism.js prism.css your_login@servername.com:~
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Your files have been uploaded onto your server. Now you need to move them into your Ghost theme directory. Login and type.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ mv prism.js /var/www/directoryghost/content/themes/casper/assets/js/
$ mv prism.css /var/www/directoryghost/content/themes/casper/assets/css/
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Now you need to edit &lt;code&gt;default.hbs&lt;/code&gt; file which resides inside your default theme folder.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cd /var/www/directoryghost/content/themes/casper/
$ nano default.hbs
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add this code &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;stylesheet&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text/css&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;{{asset &amp;quot;css/prism.css&amp;quot;}}&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;
on the beginning of the file, it should look similarly to this&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;meta name=&amp;quot;viewport&amp;quot; content=&amp;quot;width=device-width, initial-scale=1.0&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;

&amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;shortcut icon&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;{{asset &amp;quot;favicon.ico&amp;quot;}}&amp;quot;&amp;gt;

{{! Styles&#39;n&#39;Scripts }}
&amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;stylesheet&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text/css&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;{{asset &amp;quot;css/screen.css&amp;quot;}}&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;stylesheet&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text/css&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;//fonts.googleapis.com/css?family=Noto+Serif:400,700,400italic|Open+Sans:700,$

// Here
&amp;lt;link rel=&amp;quot;stylesheet&amp;quot; type=&amp;quot;text/css&amp;quot; href=&amp;quot;{{asset &amp;quot;css/prism.css&amp;quot;}}&amp;quot; /&amp;gt;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;And this code &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;{{asset &amp;quot;js/prism.js&amp;quot;}}&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; near the end.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{! The main JavaScript file for Casper }}
&amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;{{asset &amp;quot;js/jquery.fitvids.js&amp;quot;}}&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;
&amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;{{asset &amp;quot;js/index.js&amp;quot;}}&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;

//Here
&amp;lt;script type=&amp;quot;text/javascript&amp;quot; src=&amp;quot;{{asset &amp;quot;js/prism.js&amp;quot;}}&amp;quot;&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/script&amp;gt;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now restart Ghost. If you are using &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.digitalocean.com/?refcode=398e0cb398b4&#34;&gt;DigitalOcean&lt;/a&gt;, simply type &lt;code&gt;$ service ghost restart&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;testing&#34;&gt;Testing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Edit one of your posts and add a section at the end which looks similarly to mine (when I was creating my custom prism file, I added support for &lt;code&gt;javascript&lt;/code&gt; if you hadn&amp;rsquo;t, simply change &lt;em&gt;javascript&lt;/em&gt; into some language name which your prism version supports).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt; \`\`\`javascript // Remove slashes
 var x = 5;       // Declare x, give it the value of 5
 \`\`\`           // Remove slashes
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you done everything right you should see something similar to this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-javascript&#34;&gt;var x = 5;      // Declare x, give it the value of 5
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thats it! You have done it!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>work more</title>
      <link>https://pawelropa.github.io/post/work-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2014 13:57:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelropa.github.io/post/work-more/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;##Love work&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few days back I have read terrific post about work by &lt;a href=&#34;http://tynan.com/lovework&#34;&gt;Tynan&lt;/a&gt;. One of comments contained a link to an article about Mr Thomas Edison, more specific an &lt;a href=&#34;https://mises.org/daily/4986&#34;&gt;interview&lt;/a&gt; with him. I clicked the link and started reading. To my surprise I&amp;rsquo;ve read Edison&amp;rsquo;s answer to one of the question&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Well,&amp;rdquo; he replied, &amp;ldquo;for 15 years I have worked on an average of 20 hours a day.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well that&amp;rsquo;s almost insane. Since about a year I&amp;rsquo;ve done 50-60 hours work weeks, that&amp;rsquo;s above average for most of the people, thus I considered myself a hard-working man, well I don&amp;rsquo;t anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Success&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How does one achieve success? Mr Edison, one of the most successful people ever lived, gave us some advice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You do something all day long, don&amp;rsquo;t you? Everyone does. If you get up at seven o&amp;rsquo;clock and go to bed at eleven, you have put in sixteen good hours, and it is certain with most men, that they have been doing something all the time. They have been either walking, or reading, or writing, or thinking. &lt;strong&gt;The only trouble is that they do it about a great many things and I do it about one.&lt;/strong&gt; If they took the time in question and applied it in one direction, to one object, they would succeed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Success is sure to follow such application. The trouble lies in the fact that &lt;strong&gt;people do not have an object — one thing to which they stick, letting all else go&lt;/strong&gt;. Success is the product of the severest kind of mental and physical application.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will follow his advice, focus on one thing and one thing only, namely iOS and web development.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>remote office not required</title>
      <link>https://pawelropa.github.io/post/remote-office-not-required/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Dec 2013 20:50:33 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelropa.github.io/post/remote-office-not-required/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today I have read for the second time terrific book &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/17YJc1C&#34;&gt;Remote by Jason Fried &amp;amp; David Heinemeier Hansson&lt;/a&gt;. I feel like the book deserves a review so I will write a little summary of each chapter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;####The Time is Right For Remote Work&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why work doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen at work.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yes I know what they are talking about. When I was working nine-to-five job if I wanted to be really productive I had to come early or stay late to get my job done. Socializing, office politics usually takes big chunk of working hours, there is simply no way around it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stop commuting your life away.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting to the office and back to home is inefficient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s the technology, stupid.&lt;/strong&gt; All the technology is there to make remote work possible. The reason people still work in office is humans resist change.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;City as talent hub.&lt;/strong&gt; Why not expand area where you can find talented people, why search only in your city or country?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You&amp;rsquo;re probably already doing it.&lt;/strong&gt; If you are a software developer you most certainly worked for your company from your home. Some feature has to be done by tomorrow?&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;####Dealing With Excuses&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Trusting your employes.&lt;/strong&gt; One of many excuses is if I can&amp;rsquo;t see my employees, how do I know if the are working or not? It basically comes down to trust, generally people enjoy working (I certainly do). Don&amp;rsquo;t you trust a programmer you are paying salary? Why hire him in the first place? If someone want to stay idle and do nothing all day, he will.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Loosing control.&lt;/strong&gt;  You don&amp;rsquo;t have to see your employes to know what they are doing, again it all comes down to trust, people want to create and work.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Big business is already doing it.&lt;/strong&gt; IBM, S.C., Johnson &amp;amp; Son, eBay have some of theirs employees working remotely.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;####How to Collaborate Remotely&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working remotely requires compromise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Thou shalt overlap.&lt;/strong&gt; Members of your team are geographically dispersed, that means different time zones. You have to set hours in which all of your members will be available online. Four hours overlap time proposed by the authors seems reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sharing a screen.&lt;/strong&gt; Sometimes is easier to describe something by showing it, but your colleague is one thousand mils away, how do you do this? Use a shared screen software like &lt;em&gt;WebEx&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;GoToMeeting&lt;/em&gt; or any other similar tool.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Keep everything accessible to everyone&lt;/strong&gt; Share your calendar, what to do next, files or anything you are working on online.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Forward motion.&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Everyone chimes in with a few lines about what they&amp;rsquo;ve done over the past week and what&amp;rsquo;s intended for the next week.&lt;/em&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s very simple solution to keep everybody informed about the current status of projects and company.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The work is what matters.&lt;/strong&gt; You evaluate only what your employee has done. Any other criteria are unnecessary&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;####Beware the Dragons&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Isolation is bad for you&lt;/strong&gt; Occasional meetings face to face are good for the team.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To much work.&lt;/strong&gt; Usually remote workers will get too much stuff done, that&amp;rsquo;s because it is easy to stretch ones workday from 7am to 9pm, which repeated will eventually leed to burnout. Establish reasonable expectations.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ergonomic basics.&lt;/strong&gt; Get proper desk, proper chair, and proper screen.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clients.&lt;/strong&gt; Inform your clients early you will not meet face-to-face. Provide references before client even asks.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;####Hiring and Keeping the Best&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s a big world.&lt;/strong&gt; Think internationally when it comes to recruitment, it will dramatically increase your talent pool.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t keep poisonous people.&lt;/strong&gt; Monitor your work atmosphere, one bad apple spoils bunch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Great workers.&lt;/strong&gt; It&amp;rsquo;s much harder to fake your way as remote worker. Everything is being tracked, it has to be. Quiet but productive workers can shine.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Writing.&lt;/strong&gt; Being a good writer is very important. People communicate usually by mail or IM, thus expressing one thoughts clearly is very important.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Meeting them in person.&lt;/strong&gt; its very important.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;####Managing Remote Workers&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;** Meetings** Get together from time to time. Meetings are great way to introduce new people to the team.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Learn from open source.&lt;/strong&gt; Some of open source projects are very complex. Majority of work is being done by remote collaboration and communication. You should look more closely at how exactly it&amp;rsquo;s being done.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One-on-ones.&lt;/strong&gt; Do casual meetings from time to time. It will help you monitor morale and motivation of your team.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scarcity.&lt;/strong&gt; If meetings are scarce we tend to value them more. They also seem more interesting.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;####Life As A Remote Worker&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Routine.&lt;/strong&gt; Differentiate work and play time. Develop routine, it will help your mind to recognize the difference between work and other activities. Otherwise it&amp;rsquo;s probable everything will start to mix together and you won&amp;rsquo;t be able to tell when you actually worked.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Coffee shops.&lt;/strong&gt; Solitude is bad for you, change your environment from time to time, go to coffee shop or library and work from there.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nomadic freedom.&lt;/strong&gt; You can work from anywhere in the world, why wait till retirement, you can start traveling now!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Remote is terrific book&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I enjoyed reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/17YJc1C&#34;&gt;Remote&lt;/a&gt; very much and encourage you to read it also. You most certainly won&amp;rsquo;t be disappointed, it also might change your life for better.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>appcode vs xcode</title>
      <link>https://pawelropa.github.io/post/appcode-vs-xcode/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2013 13:49:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelropa.github.io/post/appcode-vs-xcode/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;App Code&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have bought &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jetbrains.com/objc/&#34;&gt;AppCode&lt;/a&gt; about 8 months ago and have been using it sence then. It has a lot of features (especially in version 2.5.x JetBrains guys added some crazy ones). Currently some of the main ones are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Support for CocoaPods!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;UnitTest status&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Great refactoring support!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Lots of plugins&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Fuzzy autocompletition&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Features I don&amp;rsquo;t use, or wish they were.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Git, Mercurial support - I find using console much more productive, &lt;em&gt;git st&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;git aa&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;git ci -m &amp;ldquo;Done some stuff&amp;rdquo;&lt;/em&gt; bam done! No mouse clicking, no nothing!&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Debugger console won&amp;rsquo;t hide after finishing debugging session. I do most of my work on &lt;em&gt;15 inch MacBook Pro&lt;/em&gt; and extra pixels are really important.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Apple is pushing really hard on using Storyboards, AppCode don&amp;rsquo;t have this feature (and probably won&amp;rsquo;t have it in the future).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;###Xcode&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Xcode 3 was pretty decent (not counting occasional crashes), in 4 Apple used more multithreading which caused sometimes unexpected behavior and occasional crashes, I didn&amp;rsquo;t liked it. A month ago I figured few months have passed since Apple released Xcode 5, and few bug fixes it&amp;rsquo;s time to give it a try (use it more than one day).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First what annoys me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes when I run Unit Tests, I get notification center message &amp;ldquo;Test Failed&amp;rdquo; despite that all tests have passed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Xcode lacks proper refactoring features if compared with AppCode. I didn&amp;rsquo;t notice it before but after using AppCode for longer period of time I miss it badly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list would be much longer if not for great plugins which are currently available for Xcode! Below list of plugins which I find most useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/mneorr/Alcatraz&#34;&gt;Alcatraz&lt;/a&gt; plugin manager&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/chendo/FuzzyAutocompletePlugin&#34;&gt;FuzzyAutocomplete&lt;/a&gt; name speaks for itself&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/JugglerShu/XVim&#34;&gt;XVim&lt;/a&gt; great Vim plugin with customization options&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also use many code snippets, they also boost my productivity.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fountainhead - Ayn Rand</title>
      <link>https://pawelropa.github.io/post/the-fountainhead-ayn-rand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 20:19:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelropa.github.io/post/the-fountainhead-ayn-rand/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are thousands, maybe even millions of books already written. They contain all human knowledge, however many of them aren’t worth reading, meaning our time on planet Earth is limited, thus one should read only books which worth is greatest. Some books have the power to change your life for better. Those are hard to find, especially because every one of us has different criteria of what better is. For some, better life means good relationships with others, for others it can be having more money, more challenges in live, possibility of pursuing ones dreams and visions. The list can go on and on. Looking from entrepreneur perspective, great masterpiece of Ayn Rand, &lt;em&gt;The Fountainhead&lt;/em&gt; deserves to be noticed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The novel is of considerable length, over seven hundreds pages, full of wisdom and rich in philosophy of Ayn Rand – Objectivsm. I encourage you to read the book from cover to cover – it’s worth it. Main character’s name is Howard Roark. He is a recently expelled student who wants to be an architect. Main reason of his expulsion is constant refusal of philosophy which majority of architects believe in. He want to create modern buildings where every part is essential for the whole structure, there can’t be unnecessary parts. Company of architects wish to build big blobs of mixed styles. The more parts taken from as many different styles the better, no logic, no design. Organization standard is &lt;em&gt;don’t use your brain, don’t try to think, just copy someone else building&lt;/em&gt;. Howard refuse to work like that, he is a man who doesn’t consider their opinions of established standards for buildings, and thus the story begins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The story line is rich, and contains many vivid characters, Gay Weynand (owner of big publishing company), Dominic Francone (very smart and beautiful woman, despises world around her), Elsworth Toohey (“a friend of the people”), Peter Kitting (an architect which compromises with the world). Each and every character has their own philosophy, which determines their actions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have read the Fountainhead more than three times already, and don’t have enough. Looking from entrepreneur perspective I find it exceptionally motivating. Fighting adversity, conquering difficulties, winning challenges, pursuing ones dreams, it’s whats all man are suppose to do. Don’t settle on lesser goals, dream big. Steve Jobs once sad&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because the people who are crazy enough to think they can change the world, are the ones who do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and I completely agree with him. The book shows the value of reasoning and logic in accomplishing what we want for ourself. It elevates the value of working hard and shows that perseverance can move the mountains. Difficulties, struggle will come if your dream is big enough. You must believe in yourself during hard days. You are an individual, a human being, you will conquer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book is also rich in philosophy of Objectivism. Which was defined by Ayn Rand. It basically redefines what is and isn’t moral. For example Objectivism redefines the meaning of egoism, and sacrifice or rather gives them their true meaning. Let’s say you are working on a big project, you have put a month of hard work into creating a product and tomorrow is your’s launch day, suddenly one of your friend calls and asks you to come over to help him renovate bike, which he has bought recently. Now if helping your friend is more valuable to you than the product you are going to launch tommorow, then you should go and help your friend – it’s not sacrifice, you choose to do more valuable thing for you. On the other hand if you project is more valuable to you, helping your friend would be a sacrifice. She propose than man should never choose lesser value, ergo man should never sacrifice. Ayn Rand points out that its a moral thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book is a treasure and I will recommend it to anyone who has doubts as to which path take in life.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slight Edge - Jeff Olson</title>
      <link>https://pawelropa.github.io/post/slight-edge-jeff-olson/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 20:02:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelropa.github.io/post/slight-edge-jeff-olson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s short post will be about another great book namely &lt;em&gt;Slight Edge&lt;/em&gt; by Jeff Olson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had to sum up the whole book in one sentance it would be - every day routine matters greatly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all have this little day to day task, some are boring some are exciting, the problem with all is &lt;em&gt;we simply stop doing them after few days or months&lt;/em&gt;. Reason? There will be no significant difference if we will not do those 10 pushups. Two months later comes this thought, &lt;em&gt;oh gosh I had this commitment, where would I be now if i had done it everyday&amp;hellip; to late to start now&amp;hellip;&lt;/em&gt; That&amp;rsquo;s how most of the people usualy end theirs commitments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jeff in his book writes about this kind of problems. His advices are simple but effective. I wish I had read &lt;em&gt;Slight Edge&lt;/em&gt; when I was in my teens, but theres never to late to improve ones life and read &lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/16zHrno&#34;&gt;his terrific book&lt;/a&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>becoming a minimalist</title>
      <link>https://pawelropa.github.io/post/becoming-a-minimalist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 19:58:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://pawelropa.github.io/post/becoming-a-minimalist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Since last year I have been reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.theminimalists.com/&#34;&gt;the minimalists blog&lt;/a&gt;. At first the idea of minimalism seemed silly to me, why would anybody willingly give up stuff, after all majority of people work so hard to get this new TV, or dress or whatever it is. The concept intrigued me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last month doing my daily routine, reading &lt;a href=&#34;http://news.ycommbinator.com&#34;&gt;hacker news&lt;/a&gt; I have encountered a blog post &lt;a href=&#34;http://levels.io/bootstrapping-startup-thailand/&#34;&gt;startup in Thailand&lt;/a&gt;. Cool story, I liked it so much that I have read this guy whole blog. Peter (that is his name) is also a minimalist, this was the drop that spilled the cup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am currently bootstrapping my own company, I have released four apps to date:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/19OHLku&#34;&gt;&lt;del&gt;Zen Blocks&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/195mHnm&#34;&gt;&lt;del&gt;Tip % Calculator&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/1asZv3r&#34;&gt;&lt;del&gt;Gem Crush&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://bit.ly/19Qlz7k&#34;&gt;&lt;del&gt;Memory Fish&lt;/del&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and distractions decrease my productivity. Removing all my stuff and leaving only my MacBook Pro, iPad, and iPhone to work with should in theory make me more productive. I am really excited starting this new journey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I am officially a minimalist&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>