<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy on Big Cube</title>
    <link>/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philosophy on Big Cube</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 20:19:40 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Fountainhead - Ayn Rand</title>
      <link>/post/the-fountainhead-ayn-rand/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2013 20:19:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/the-fountainhead-ayn-rand/</guid>
      <description>There are thousands, maybe even millions of books already written. They contain all human knowledge, however many of them aren’t worth reading, meaning our time on planet Earth is limited, thus one should read only books which worth is greatest. Some books have the power to change your life for better. Those are hard to find, especially because every one of us has different criteria of what better is. For some, better life means good relationships with others, for others it can be having more money, more challenges in live, possibility of pursuing ones dreams and visions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Becoming a minimalist</title>
      <link>/post/becoming-a-minimalist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 19:58:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/becoming-a-minimalist/</guid>
      <description>Since last year I have been reading the minimalists blog. At first the idea of minimalism seemed silly to me, why would anybody willingly give up stuff, after all majority of people work so hard to get this new TV, or dress or whatever it is. The concept intrigued me.
Last month doing my daily routine, reading hacker news I have encountered a blog post startup in Thailand. Cool story, I liked it so much that I have read this guy whole blog.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>